We're going to move out of two down, our guest is not here, so we're going to skip it until you get there.
So go three public input, let's get to the personal preferences.
Have none. Four claims.
Thank you.
Five minutes from the December 18th, 2023.
Mr. Chair.
You said five, don't go to parties.
Five.
Six.
The election resolution, CC, 2024, dashed here on calling for proclaiming and ordering a non-partisan general election in the city of Maya.
How do I count me?
I'm going to say about one on the, on Tuesday, April 2nd, 2024.
For the purpose of electing the city council members for award three, southwest and ward four, southeast.
Motion.
Take.
September.
Williams.
April 5th.
He stepped up.
A partner.
Hi.
Seven.
Renew and Elsafore support agreement with M&M Micro Systems for police records in the amount of 15,000.
This is an annual contract.
So for animals, for us, it's our reporting system that we do all our reports and set.
And just an annual contract.
Motion.
Take.
Hi.
Williams.
Hey.
He stepped up.
Sender.
Hi.
A user agency agreement with Oklahoma law enforcement of telecommunication system.
Oklahoma Department of Public Safety for reading the license points.
This is our new boss for our cameras and cars.
We have three units that will have license papers.
The other of these are the sky.
I have recreated on tini advisory those.
I have a.
Oh, let's control that information.
We have a user agreement for.
I'll let terminal dispatch.
This will be the somewhat I support.
With watch cards.
They get in and cars.
So this built into course.
The built to the car.
Do you like the car.
Do we have cars going home?
These are not no.
These won't go back.
These are our normal languages.
They are not assigned as a subcopter.
They're resilient.
But if you're getting a third whole part of it, everybody drives.
And that's what it is.
Whether it's good for that.
So they're used to 247.
So will they be on all three of you on every shift?
Yes.
Most of them through.
Second.
Circle.
Eastern.
Williams.
Hi.
Perfect.
How you got a quick question?
Hastings.
Whenever they scan those plates, and then they go into the system in the car, they automatically
do a check on the tag or they just pop up.
It will do a check on the tag like it will pop up in the car's phone or
or and it shares that information.
We get requests every day for the Department of Public Country.
So, if I say tag pops up here or learn that agency or if they report it stolen somewhere else
and pop up for us.
It's a suspect that something is here somewhere.
And that is Rachel Pop up.
So, hi.
This one is anything to add.
So, it's great information sharing.
And we had one that I felt much going to think.
The grant to artists.
Park, park, pop up.
That's the sole vehicle.
And you call this a hat.
I can't put that one in here.
But.
The car's part of the grant to pop up.
Pull in.
Williams.
You got a sole vehicle.
I was just from the last career.
Two stars.
to fire all that up there. So, it's an action, I wonder where we're moving here.
Just for the contract, we're going to agree with where the contract is.
Motion will prove. Second.
Oh yeah, we already did that. Sorry, you're right.
No.
And I, of course, you're going with the axel on enterprises and pay the balance of $10,526 to $20.
For your expensive tonight.
I'm especially glad that this is our tasers.
We've been using taser settings.
We were able to use some grant money from the charity nation.
And instead of having five to the share and you get trade ownership,
every control officer will have their own taser.
So, it puts a lot of this where I'm in.
We really have life and grandfathers, this is our
child's work out role, so we are really set forward for the project.
It's just a crew we can get that contract and pay the balance.
Motion, please.
Take it.
Don't pull.
Stand up.
What are you going to do?
He's set.
Pardon.
Thank you.
You're going to see.
Tantons subscription to next poll.
For grant writer grant finder in the amount of 1,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000.
Let's the poll grant finder is exactly what it says it is.
It finds grants.
It's an online system that we event access to for some time, but in the past we had access
through a contract with OML, but it was for a single license, it was only 50 bucks, but
that there's no longer offered to OML, the local of the Esports League.
So we have to go with the subscription to the company, which is annual for $1400 and $95, however,
we get to the four licenses and the value to us well exceeds the cost of the software.
In finding grants, it allows us to go in and not only identify specific grants that we may
be looking for for specific projects, but we can set up watching and say, here's the projects
we've got coming up in the future and it will continue to watch for those types of grants to pop
up and notify and send alerts when it sees grants like that, they're identified.
Again, we've used it for quite a while, but with the four licenses now, we'll
be able to use it, we'll have one at the CBB, one at the Coleman, Glendis gonna retain one
and Cali to library, one at one, and primarily these grants are four or five or one, C3s, so
that's why those areas specifically will be used in the future, but our library at CBB and Coleman
in Glendis, we'll use it, thanks for seeing how far we're known, I'm sure one grant is paid for.
So CBB, with their license, they'll be able to go in and write their own, send that library.
Well, they'll be able to be able to do it in key information that it's looking for, trying to find
the grants for them, so we don't have a identify grants that are out there, federal or state, but then
we'll have them write them all, well, different people, yeah, but it helps with the majority of them, you know,
Cali, they were really good at writing a lot of their own grants, Tyler does, I think a lot of he's a
grants, but Glendis always good to support anybody in the organization that can tell.
This is the same service we've used for a while in a different way of paying for it, never way paid for it.
What's your proof?
Second.
Williams.
Here.
Hi.
Is that?
No, please.
Is that for me?
Okay.
Hi.
We're there.
Hello.
I hope date and pause.
I actually hope you would class action lawsuit against Kinsey and company and corporate.
As you all recall, the last meeting we talked about is whether we were the same
or state and this last action.
It's a state and we don't know.
Would you recommend a recommendation that we do stay in?
I don't know.
We don't have to do anything.
If we still have seen a reason, we shouldn't stay in.
So you don't need action for an stay in.
Hey, about one out of doubt.
About a twelve.
For award lease purchase agreement, to first national bank, for C-23-67.
Pirate captain's truck.
We have related signing and payment authority to the city manager is doesn't need.
The interest rates are very close.
I choose the sign of that.
The rate is as big as national $365.
So anyway, all of the issues still came out.
What is the captain's trip?
The officer in charge of that big hit.
What do we have now?
I can most of it prove.
No second.
Hi.
Thank you.
13 other new business.
Many of which are the residents of the post of this agenda.
14 staff support.
15 mayor and council committee announcements.
I'm just talking to people around town going to very soliday events.
Everybody's talking about the progress that's going on.
It's really awesome.
It's really awesome to be a part of it.
It's awesome to hear people just acknowledge that we're making progress.
And that things are happening.
And I'm just glad to be a part of it.
We have 2023 was the kickoff.
And we need to make 2024 a blue city keep pushing.
I'm just probably a part of this team.
Everybody here and all the things that we did last year.
And the year before.
And it's just building and building.
And I'm excited to see what happens in the next year.
No, good.
I know you.
Well, just about along with Brian said.
I hear a lot of the same stuff.
And it's really nice to see everybody pulling in the same direction.
Everybody is excited.
He's muted.
He's excited.
I can see it.
The administration.
Everybody's moving in the same direction.
It's nice to see.
To hear the hear the community.
He excited about the stuff that's happening.
It's pretty cool because it hasn't been that way in a while.
I appreciate all the staff's efforts.
And then boy's efforts.
Because we couldn't do it, not you.
You guys are.
You guys are going to a great job.
Bo does a great job.
I think what I hear from the staff is.
And I don't know if they're out loud enough.
And they say this.
But you're one of the best they've had.
Sounds like for most of them anyway.
They've been here.
So I appreciate your efforts with the change of culture that was.
It was needed.
And I think you can see that through the police, so I appreciate the guys downtown trying to pick down Christmas.
I know it's a daunting task, but they're giving them an appreciate your guys' tolerance.
I know they got a job and do the pop of that and Kevin's get guys do too, but getting that all taken down.
It's probably a tour of those things wrapped up in that, but downtown looked great, so I appreciate all your efforts for the years.
The guys did down there, and I'm also excited about what's going on in 2024.
We got a lot still coming, but a lot of people don't even know about that, so it'll be good to go.
And I'd like to say, there must be some stuff going on in Miami because my wife noticed.
And she doesn't normally notice that stuff.
She's saying, man, a lot of things happen around town.
Well, I think, yeah, the comments that you all make about the team up here and not only the city team.
The importance of everybody working together, this is what makes a difference in Miami, we've heard that from our state partners.
We hear it from our other communities.
My name is really lucky to have a group up here, like you all that communicate well, that get along, that don't always have to agree.
But aren't disagreeable. You can have conversations and work through them and come to a consensus that everybody can live with.
And that's what moves allows us to move forward.
The city team is a lot the same way. They're all working and pull on the road in the same direction.
And it makes a big difference when everybody's working together because guys, it takes a village to do everything that we're doing.
And so I think that's just what's making all the difference. Everybody's working together.
But all the differences aside, even working with the communities around us makes a difference.
But I think everybody can feel that. That's what everybody gets excited about.
It's not only what we've done, what we can do in the near future, but the potential is off the chart.
Congrats to you all and all you've done.
Appreciate what you all bring to this and you make much of a lot easier.
I know there's a lot of city managers that tell me horror stories of going to their council meetings on a regular basis, and it's just a cluster every time.
It's a big argument that everybody's fighting, nobody agrees. We just don't have back here.
It's not that we all agree all the time, but again, nobody's disagreeable. You all could talk for it and come to consensus.
So thank you all for all your time and effort you put it to this.
Thank you.
We're going to go back to number two because I think our guests are right.
Another two is the presentation of Grant Award from USDA rule development.
Mr. Kevin Gordon.
Thank you for the opportunity to be here tonight.
I apologize for running late.
So we're on the tour around Tulsa.
I was going to go back past the exit.
And you're going to last problem.
I've had the opportunity to do it.
I've done the GPS of the now.
It's a good team.
It's also this view.
But thank you for the opportunity to be here tonight.
And we're not a good partner with your city, USDA woke development.
It's probably the lesser known of the USDA agency.
So when people hear about roll development,
or USDA, they immediately think about cows, and farms,
and meat processing.
I'm going to be tons of been places that I last been about.
How we inspect meat, and I have no idea.
On the one guy probably at this part of our corporate.
of our corporate that doesn't know a whole lot about the
at our corporate portion of what we do.
However, what we do at World Development is
we help our rural communities
get the infrastructure things they need.
We say we can finance our,
or in private grants.
We can build a city,
and learn around that.
So we're involved from schools,
the hospitals, for roads,
bridges to electric systems,
you name it,
we do it all at World Development.
And so we have a number of programs
that I don't know,
my am a particularly good,
could qualify for one,
and are a really utility program.
We have our,
you know,
you're an electric city,
power city.
So that program is available.
We'll be able to be financing.
We can tell you that,
which I've known this from
I was city manager.
The financing opportunities for
world development,
or much better than what I found anywhere else.
The interest rate is lower.
There's no pay off penalties.
And you have the ability to finance
at a much longer period of time.
You do through
conventional financing,
so that's something you can demand.
But we also have the world business development grant,
which can be used for communities to do things for
a lot,
can't be used for some of the structure things
if you can show this.
Going to help the small,
emerging business.
I think it also will be used for work,
which development as well.
But over here,
to not present is that,
that's the award that we did with our community
to solve this program.
Our community to solve this program is probably
the flagship program in the world development.
Now a lot of people know about it,
but it is a grant and loan program.
The loan program is a
great program on it.
It's just a funny thing.
You need the community from
lease cars,
fire trucks,
to just about any time
of the project you have,
community center,
hospitals and things like that.
Again,
it has a very low interest rate
and a long period of time with pay off.
But the car I'm here
to do not support the grant portion.
And we have a grant portion.
That allows us to help communities
with things such as police cars and car trucks.
And we've got a number of things across the state.
I'm real pleased with my staff this year.
We only got $370,000 to give us this year
to allocate the communities across the home.
But what happens at World Development
is that every year,
they do a pooling in August.
And so states that don't use their
allocations.
So my friends had the same job I have in California,
and I can thank them this year
because they didn't spend all their money.
So I end up being able to help.
with about $1.9 million dollars and right funds across the state for a little community
sooner or later because we were prepared for when the polling happened that we
sooner everybody's application that we still had left in our office forward.
So I tell people just because the first round we don't have any money does it mean we're
not going to have money.
So go ahead and put your applications in and your city was one of one that we managed to
slide and give it a little higher amount than what we normally did.
It's capped at $50,000 and we're going to the polling sometimes we can do more and we
might be able to do a partnership with you, $53,500 to help you with equipment that you need
to do your code enforcement to the bank initiative.
So I don't know the mayor or the worker, but if you guys looking down on this, I'm not going
to get someone to take a picture for you, I'm going to let's go.
You guys really helped me out in a great deal when we had a nice one come through.
Here's your cruise you sent from your city to the fantastic to help you out in your city or
as hard.
I could figure out how I could pay you the money while I was paying my child, I thought I was going
to sell all of your guys.
I thought good afternoon.
They did one heck of a good job of him.
They weren't told.
They asked me to hold them off the line so I appreciate that we can do this.
So you grew up in the city.
You actually give to this a bench?
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah.
I appreciate that.
They never should really do this in a bench for a tent and what was it about?
Right.
We appreciate you guys sitting right there.
We were down there first all in the mail.
Yeah.
And you had it.
I remember.
Yeah.
We worked with lots of this job.
I remember right.
Those they got them for all that.
And we did.
Well, we certainly appreciate this.
Thank you guys for letting.
this was very timely. We went to a great use. We got a lot of great equipment for trucks, trailers,
motors, motors, weed eaters. I think we would got some body cams and a couple of trucks
for public workshop. It was a pretty laundry list that came up to, we spent about 100,000 on it,
and we spent another 53,000 helpers do on that.
So, thank you. We'll see you at the same time next year.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Can you get us one of the copies of one of the pictures?
Yes, we don't feel it.
Okay, I'll sit down with you.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Motion, second.
All right.
Williams.
Hi.